SOYKAN GÖKSEL KAMAL

Antalya/Turkey 07230, +90(546) 284-1389, soykangokselkamal@gmail.com @ GitHub @ LinkedIn @ itch.io

SUMMARY

Unity developer with 2 years of experience and a passion for game design and development. Excels at Hyper Casual and Casual game development. Built and shipped a total of 7 games. Published on Google Play Store, Windows and WebGL platforms. Worked on iOS App Store in previous job experience. Seeking to use proven development and design skills to assist your development team.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

- Unity3D
- UnityCinemachine
- UnityNavMesh
- Programming Languages (C, C++, Python, Java)
- Unity2D
- UnityTimeline
- Data Persistence
- Google Play Services (Ads, In-app Purchases, Leaderboard, ...)
- C#
- UnityRecorder
- Windows Platform
- Google Play Store Game Publishing & Android Platform
- Unity Shaders
- Mecanim
- WebGL Platform
- iOS App Store Game Publishing & iOS Platform

EDUCATION

Middle East Technical University (METU)

-B.S. in Engineering Sciences (Computer Engineering)

- Overall GPA: 3.14/4, Graduated as an Honor Student
- Design Project: Casual Auto-battler Genre Game Project for the Android Platform (Sponsored/Contracted Work)
- Achievements: Rank #1 in C Programming Course, Multiple Honor Certificates, 91.5/100 English Proficiency Score

RELEVANT EXPERIENCE

5x5 Gaming & METU

-Unity Game Developer (Casual, Mobile (Android) & Windows) [Contracted]

(Sep. 2020 – Jul. 2021) Güzelyurt, Turkey

(Sept. 2016-Jul. 2021)

Güzelyurt, Turkey

Led a team of senior student Unity developers on a Casual Android game project. Scheduled development sprints and assigned team members. Supervised the development. Chaired with the professor in charge and the sponsor to evaluate the progress. Planned and regulated the testing procedure. Programmed the general gameplay, fighting mechanic, in-game currency & purchase mechanics, and several other systems. Conducted game review surveys. Produced a development document summarizing the process.

Omnio Games

(Feb. 2021 - Mar. 2021)

-Unity Game Developer (Hyper Casual, Mobile (iOS)) [Internship]

Istanbul, Turkey

Programmed Hyper Casual games for the iOS App Store platform. Collaborated with game designers and designed engaging, fun and hit game mechanics. Examined the iOS US App Store to detect trending mechanics and genres. Built the decided mechanics into game projects. Cooperated with product managers to analyze published games' performance metrics.

Adesso Turkey

(Aug. 2020 – Oct. 2020)

-Software Engineer [Internship]

İstanbul, Turkey

Developed a program to fill out a SQL database from a given big data in the form of an Excel sheet using Python language.

LaciTek İleri Teknolojiler

(Jul. 2019 – Aug. 2019)

-Software Engineer [Internship]

İzmir, Turkey

Programmed several applications written in C language. Analyzed pre-written code segments, debugged and fixed errors.

HONORS AND AWARDS

- Second place at PURA GAME JAM'22
- EESTEC Game Jam'21 Contestant

- HUJAM Game Jam'22 Contestant
- 3x Honor Student & Honor Graduate

LEADERSHIP ROLES

5x5 Gaming & METU, Student Engineering Team Lead

(Sep. 2020 - Jul. 2021)

- Led a team of Unity developers on a game project. Partitioned the project into sprints and assigned members their roles.
- Met with supervising professor and sponsor. Produced development documents and presented them weekly.

METU Powerlifting Society & Powerlifting Team, Vice President

(May. 2019 – Jul. 2021)

• Organized weekly meetings and activities for the powerlifting community at METU.